[
  {
    "question_text": "The Alps in northern Italy are an example of Which of the following types of tectonic boundaries?",
    "category": "EARTH_SPACE",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "W",
    "option_1": "Continental-continental convergence",
    "option_2": "Continental-oceanic convergence",
    "option_3": "Oceanic-oceanic convergence",
    "option_4": "Continental-continental divergence",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Identify all of the following three landmarks that are usually glacial in origin: 1)Kettle lake;2)Intermittent stream;3)Submarine valley.",
    "category": "EARTH_SPACE",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "1ONLY",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Which of the following compounds violates the octet rule?",
    "category": "CHEMISTRY",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "W",
    "option_1": "Sulfur tetrafluoride",
    "option_2": "Ozone",
    "option_3": "Dinitrogen tetroxide",
    "option_4": "Phosphorus trichloride",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Which of the following inorganic acids has the highest p Ka?",
    "category": "CHEMISTRY",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "X",
    "option_1": "Sulfuric acid",
    "option_2": "Hydrofluoric acid",
    "option_3": "Perchloric acid",
    "option_4": "Nitric acid",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Tay- Sachs disease is caused by a 4 base pair insertion into the hexosaminidase (read: hex-oh-sah-MIN-ee-days) A gene. This 4 base pair insertion is an example of what type of mutation?",
    "category": "BIOLOGY",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "FRAMESHIFTMUTATION",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "In 2007, scientists successfully induced the differentiation of a fibroblast into a stem cell. These induced stem cells have Which of the following potencies?",
    "category": "BIOLOGY",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "Z",
    "option_1": "Totipotent",
    "option_2": "Unipotent",
    "option_3": "Multipotent",
    "option_4": "Pluripotent",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Half of 1616 (read: the quantity 16 to the power of 16) can be expressed as 2raised to what power?",
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "63",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Juliet is on a ship at 0 degrees East, 60 degrees North. She sails along the 60 degree latitude line to reach Romeo at 45 degrees West, 60 degrees North. If the Earth‚Äôscircumferenceis 40,000kilometers,How manykilometersdoes Juliet travel?",
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "2500",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "MIT Researchers at the Whitehead institute are studying daily torpor, which is a state of dormancy marked by a significant drop in body temperature, low metabolic activity, and reduced food intake. In addition to daily torpor, animals living in harsh winter conditions often undergo what type ofprolonged torpor?",
    "category": "ENERGY",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "HIBERNATION",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Researchers in the Ovchinnikov (read: ov-CHIN-ee-kov) Group developed a heuristic to efficiently search for high-scoring phylogenetic trees. What principle is used to score phylogenetic treesby the total number ofcharacter-state changes?",
    "category": "ENERGY",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "PRINCIPLE OF MAXIMUM PARSIMONY (ACCEPT: MAXIMUM PARSIMONY, PARSIMONY,OCCAM‚ÄôSRAZOR)",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Which of the following gives the magnitude and direction, respectively, of the net acceleration experienced by an object falling to the ground at its terminal velocity?",
    "category": "PHYSICS",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "Y",
    "option_1": "ùëî downward",
    "option_2": "ùëî/2(read: govertwo)downward",
    "option_3": "0",
    "option_4": "ùëî upward",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Josh places a 10-gram wooden block at rest on his desk, then applies a constant force of 10millinewtons to the block alongthedesk‚Äôssurface. Ifthecoefficients of static and kinetic friction between the block and desk are 0.6 and 0.05, respectively, what is the acceleration of the block inmeters per second squared?",
    "category": "PHYSICS",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "0",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Identify all of the following three characteristics of meandering streams that typically increaseas one moves downstream: 1)Capacity;2)Competence; 3)Gradient.",
    "category": "EARTH_SPACE",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "1ONLY",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Which of the following quadrants of a Northern Hemisphere hurricane, relative toits direction of motion, experiences the strongeststorm surge?",
    "category": "EARTH_SPACE",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "X",
    "option_1": "Left front",
    "option_2": "Right front",
    "option_3": "Left rear",
    "option_4": "Right rear",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Rickyrollsafairsix-sideddieandseesanevennumber. What is the expectedvalueofthenumber Rickysaw?",
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "4",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Acheeseburgerhas 2slicesofbreadand 1patty,andis 300calories. A Big Mac has 3 slices of bread and 2 patties, and is 560 calories. How many calories does one sliceofbreadhave?",
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "40",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Foolish rice seedling disease is characterized by rice plants growing so tall that they topple over before they can mature. This disease is associated with the hypersecretionof whichplanthormone?",
    "category": "BIOLOGY",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "GIBBERELLINS",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "The Allee (read: ah-LEE)effectstatesthatatsmallerpopula- tion sizes, per capita population growth slows. Which of the following is NOT a valid explanation forthe Alleeeffect?",
    "category": "BIOLOGY",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "Z",
    "option_1": "Atsmallerpopulationsizes,organismsaremorevulnerabletopredatorattack",
    "option_2": "Atsmallerpopulationsizes,populationsaremorelikelytoexperiencestronggeneticdrift",
    "option_3": "Atsmallerpopulationsizes,organismshaveahardertimefindingmates",
    "option_4": "Atsmallerpopulationsizes,diseasespreadsmorerapidly",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Researchers in the Kulik Group computationally studied the enzyme methane monooxygenase, which catalyzes the transformation of methane to what simple alcohol?",
    "category": "ENERGY",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "METHANOL",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Researchers in the Van der Hilst Group are using seismic imaging to study the Mohoroviƒçiƒá (read: MOH-he-ROH-vih-chitch) discontinuity. Where is the Mohoroviƒçiƒádiscontinuitylocated?",
    "category": "ENERGY",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "X",
    "option_1": "Betweentheupperandlowercrust",
    "option_2": "Betweenthelowercrustanduppermantle",
    "option_3": "Betweentheupperandlowermantle",
    "option_4": "Betweenthelowermantleandoutercore",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "A0.40molarsolutionofhydrochloricacidisusedtotitrate 25millilitersof 0.16molarsodiumhydroxide. Inmilliliters,howmuchhydrochloricacidisrequired toreachtheequivalencepoint?",
    "category": "CHEMISTRY",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "10",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "How many sigma and pi bonds, respectively, are found in thehighestcontributingresonanceformof SOF ? 4",
    "category": "CHEMISTRY",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "5SIGMA,1PI (ACCEPT:5AND1,DONOTACCEPT:1AND5)",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "In optics, the angle of incidence is always equal to Which of thefollowingangles?",
    "category": "PHYSICS",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "X",
    "option_1": "Angleofrefraction",
    "option_2": "Angleofreflection",
    "option_3": "Criticalangle",
    "option_4": "Brewster‚Äôsangle",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "A satellite is orbiting the Earth at 12,800 kilometers above the Earth‚Äôssurface. Iftheradiusofthe Earthis 6,400kilometers,thentotwosignificantfiguresandin meters per second squared, what is the gravitational acceleration experienced by the satellite due tothe Earth?",
    "category": "PHYSICS",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "1.1",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Physicists from the Kavli Institute studied the Hubble tension, which is the disparity between measurements of the universe‚Äôs current rate of expansion. What is theproposedsourcefortheacceleratingexpansionoftheuniverse?",
    "category": "ENERGY",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "DARKENERGY (DONOTACCEPT: DARKMATTER)",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Physicistsatthe Plasma Scienceand Fusion Centerarestudying tritium breeding, which produces tritium by bombarding lithium-7 with a neutron. This reaction splitstheresultinglithium-8nucleusintotritium,aneutron,andwhatothernuclide?",
    "category": "ENERGY",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "HELIUM-4(ACCEPT: ALPHAPARTICLE)",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "A10-grambilliardballtravelingat 10meterspersecondcollides perfectlyinelasticallywitha 500gramwoodenblockatrestonaflatpooltable. Inkilogram-meters persecond,What is themomentumoftheball-blocksystemafterthecollision?",
    "category": "PHYSICS",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "0.1",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Identify all of the following three systems that generate a mag- neticfield: 1)Pointchargeatrestinzeroexternalelectricfield;2)Pointchargeatrestinanonzero externalelectricfield;3)Pointchargemovinginalinewithconstantspeedinzeroexternalelectric field.",
    "category": "PHYSICS",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "3ONLY",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Identify all of the following three theorems that always apply to the absolute value function on any closed interval: 1) Intermediate value theorem; 2) Mean value theorem;3)Extremevaluetheorem.",
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "1AND3",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Eric has an 8 ounce cup of bubble tea that is currently 50% ice by volume. If Eric drinks the bubble tea until it is 80% ice by volume, and no ice melts, how many ouncesofbubbleteadidhedrink?",
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "3",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Which of the following properties of a liquid increases whenanon-volatilesoluteisaddedtoformadilutesolution?",
    "category": "CHEMISTRY",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "Z",
    "option_1": "Vaporpressure",
    "option_2": "Surfacetension",
    "option_3": "Freezingpoint",
    "option_4": "Boilingpoint",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "The first, second, and third ionization energies of an element are 500, 950, and 3500 kilojoules per mole, respectively. Which of the following is the mostlikelyidentityoftheelement?",
    "category": "CHEMISTRY",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "Y",
    "option_1": "Tellurium",
    "option_2": "Antimony",
    "option_3": "Barium",
    "option_4": "Cesium",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Moths circle around lights due to an innate response that causes them to orient themselves such that light sources are behind them. This kind of movement isageneralexampleof Which of the followingphenomena?",
    "category": "BIOLOGY",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "X",
    "option_1": "Kinesis (read: Kine-EE-sis)",
    "option_2": "Taxis (read: Tax-iss)",
    "option_3": "Tropism (read: Trope-ism)",
    "option_4": "Mimicry",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Orderthefollowingthreestepsofcellularrespirationinchrono- logical order starting from glucose: 1) Glucose phosphorylation (read: FOS-four-ill-AY-shun); 2) Cytochromecreduction;3)Citrateformation.",
    "category": "BIOLOGY",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "1,3,2",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "A star with Which of the following solar masses wouldhavethelongestlifespan?",
    "category": "EARTH_SPACE",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "Z",
    "option_1": "100",
    "option_2": "10",
    "option_3": "1",
    "option_4": "0.1",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Which of the followingtermsdescribesagalaxy withadenselypopulatedhaloandprominentdustringsformingadisk?",
    "category": "EARTH_SPACE",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "W",
    "option_1": "Lenticular",
    "option_2": "Spiral",
    "option_3": "Irregular",
    "option_4": "Elliptical",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Researchers at CSAIL‚Äôs Julia Lab improved an upper-bound on the Gaussian elimination algorithm. Which of the following tasks could Gaussian elimination directlyperform?",
    "category": "ENERGY",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "X",
    "option_1": "Removingblurringfromimage",
    "option_2": "Solvingsystemoflinearequations",
    "option_3": "Optimizingreal-valuedfunction",
    "option_4": "Findingrootstohigher-orderpolynomials",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Researchersinthe Aouad Groupstudiedstochasticprocesses where independent events occur at a constant mean rate. For these processes, the number of occurrencesinafixedtimeintervalfollowswhatfamilyofprobabilitydistributions?",
    "category": "ENERGY",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "Y",
    "option_1": "Normal",
    "option_2": "Exponential",
    "option_3": "Poisson (read: pwa-saun)",
    "option_4": "Gamma",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "A class of 48 people takes a 50-point exam. When grading the exams, the professor accidentally adds an extra three 0s at the end of someone‚Äôs score. Which of thefollowingmeasuresfortheclass‚Äôsgradeswillhavethesmallestchangeinmagnitude?",
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "X",
    "option_1": "Mean",
    "option_2": "Median",
    "option_3": "Range",
    "option_4": "Variance",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "A regular hexagon has side lengths of 2 meters. What is the ratio betweenthelengthfromthemidpointofasidetothecenterandavertextothecenter? ‚àö",
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "3/2",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Claire observes the conversion of a high energy photon near an atomicnucleustoanelectronandapositron. Thisisanexampleofwhatprocess?",
    "category": "PHYSICS",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "PAIRPRODUCTION",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "A particle‚Äôs acceleration in meters per second squared is given by the equation ùëé(ùë°) = 12ùë°2 (read: a of t equals twelve times t squared), whereùë° is the time passed inseconds. Iftheparticle‚Äôsvelocityatùë° = 0is 1meterpersecond,theninmeterspersecond,what istheparticle‚Äôsvelocityatùë° = 2?",
    "category": "PHYSICS",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "33",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "The Wolff- Chaikoff (read: Wolf-chai-cough)effectiscausedby highlevelsofwhatessentialtraceelement,usedinathyroidhormonethatincreasesbasalmetabolic ratesecretedfromthethyroid?",
    "category": "BIOLOGY",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "IODINE",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Identify all of the followingthreeorgans,thatifremoved,would causeasignificantreductioninproteinabsorptioninhumans: 1)Pancreas;2)Submandibular (read: sub-MAN-dib-you-lar)salivarygland;3)Smallintestine.",
    "category": "BIOLOGY",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "1AND3",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "When added in trace amounts to pure silicon, Which of thefollowingelementswouldcreateap-typesemiconductor?",
    "category": "CHEMISTRY",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "Z",
    "option_1": "Germanium",
    "option_2": "Phosphorus",
    "option_3": "Antimony",
    "option_4": "Gallium",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Yunyi is studying the solubility of calcium carbonate in aqueous solution, and observes his sample‚Äôs solubility decreases as temperature increases. Which of the followingbestexplains Yunyi‚Äôsobservation?",
    "category": "CHEMISTRY",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "X",
    "option_1": "Dissolvingcalciumcarbonateisendothermic",
    "option_2": "Dissolvingcalciumcarbonateisexothermic",
    "option_3": "Dissolvingcalciumcarbonateincreasethesolution‚Äôsentropy",
    "option_4": "Dissolvingcalciumcarbonatedecreasesthesolution‚Äôsentropy",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Although Mercury orbits the sun quickly, we only observe Mercury transiting the sun once about every seven years. Which of the following considerationsexplainsthispattern?",
    "category": "EARTH_SPACE",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "Z",
    "option_1": "Mercury‚Äôsorbitishighlyeccentric",
    "option_2": "Mercury‚Äôsorbitalprecessionisrapid",
    "option_3": "Mercury‚Äôstransitscanonlybeobservedwhen Mercuryisnearitsaphelion",
    "option_4": "Mercury‚Äôsorbitistiltedrelativetotheecliptic",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "In a contact binary, the two stars‚Äô respective en- velopesmeetatwhich Lagrangepoint?",
    "category": "EARTH_SPACE",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "L1(ACCEPT: LAGRANGEPOINT1)",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "How manyelectronsaretransferredpermanganeseatomin theredoxreactionbetweenpotassiumpermanganateandiron (II)chlorideinacidicsolution?",
    "category": "CHEMISTRY",
    "question_style": "SHORT_ANSWER",
    "question_type": "TOSSUP",
    "correct_answer": "5",
    "option_1": null,
    "option_2": null,
    "option_3": null,
    "option_4": null,
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Which of the following acids could not be safely stored usingglasscontainers?",
    "category": "CHEMISTRY",
    "question_style": "MULTIPLE_CHOICE",
    "question_type": "BONUS",
    "correct_answer": "W",
    "option_1": "Fluoroantimonic (read: floor-oh-anti-monic)acid",
    "option_2": "Sulfuric acid",
    "option_3": "Hydrochloricacid",
    "option_4": "Trichloroacetic (read: Tri-chloro-as-ee-tic)acid",
    "source": "MIT_2025",
    "explanation": null
  }
]